Mank is a drama, history film directed by David Fincher.
1930s Hollywood is reevaluated through the eyes of scathing
social critic and alcoholic screenwriter Herman J.
Mankiewicz as he races to finish the screenplay of Citizen Kane.
Herman Mankiewicz, played by Gary Oldman.
Marion Davies, played by Amanda Seyfried.
Rita Alexander, played by Lily Collins.
Louis B. Mayer, played by Arliss Howard.
Joseph Mankiewicz, played by Tom Pelphrey.
John Houseman, played by Sam Troughton.
Mank is a 2020 American biographical drama film about screenwriter Herman J.
Mankiewicz and his development of the screenplay for
Orson Welles's 1941 film Citizen Kane.
It was directed by David Fincher based on a screenplay written by his late father Jack
Fincher and was produced by Ceán Chaffin, Douglas Urbanski, and Eric Roth.
It stars Gary Oldman in the title role, alongside Amanda Seyfried, Lily Collins, Arliss Howard, Tom Pelphrey, Sam Troughton, Ferdinand
Kingsley, Tuppence Middleton, Tom Burke, Joseph Cross, Jamie McShane, Toby Leonard Moore, Monika Gossman, and Charles Dance.
Fincher originally intended to make Mank after he completed The Game (1997), with Kevin
Spacey and Jodie Foster as the leads, but the project did not come to fruition.
Eventually, the project was officially announced in July 2019, and filming took
place around Los Angeles from November 2019 to February 2020.
To pay homage to the films of the 1930s, Mank was shot
in black-and-white, using RED cameras.
Mank had a limited theatrical release on November 13, 2020,
and began streaming on Netflix on December 4.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who praised Fincher's direction, as well as the acting
(particularly Oldman and Seyfried), cinematography, production values, and musical score.
The film earned the leading ten nominations at the 93rd Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor
(Oldman), and Best Supporting Actress (Seyfried), and won for Best Production Design and Best Cinematography.
It received the leading six nominations at the 78th Golden Globe Awards, including Best Motion
Picture – Drama as well as the six nominations at the 74th British Academy Film Awards.
The film explores themes of movie business, screenwriter,
biography, hollywood, black and white.
The tone is emotional.